<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on ewenme</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on ewenme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>FPL Mythbusting with fplR</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-06-25-fpl_mythbusting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-06-25-fpl_mythbusting/</guid>
      <description>I recently authored my first R package (and definitely have the bug, now). It would be remiss of me to continue without a quick PSA for anyone out there thinking about dabbling in the package game - below is a shout-out of the invaluable resources I found along the way that kept me nice and sane.
ease in https://t.co/NdRYGE1whA
more detail https://t.co/ypqotSAF46
best practice https://t.co/qRMZDXBdfQ
travis 💀 https://t.co/dEvM3PWsVb — ewen (@ewen_) June 7, 2017</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring London&#39;s Pubs &amp; Bars with geofacet</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-05-30-geofacet_ldn_pubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-05-30-geofacet_ldn_pubs/</guid>
      <description>Introducing geofacet The geofacet package dropped recently (I want to say last week?), a ggplot2 extension allowing for the user to facet plots in a way that can retain an underlying geographical dimension. It perhaps goes a little bit further towards abstraction than tilegrams, but the visualizations we produce can be a bit more complex as well. This post documents my first foray into this packages functionality.1

 Getting to grips with grids If we think about faceting in ggplot2 (facet_wrap, facet_grid), we are already familiar with the idea of placing a sequence of plots into a number of panels, arranged according to a variable(s) of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Representativeness of UK Parliament</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-04-23-uk_parliament_representativeness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-04-23-uk_parliament_representativeness/</guid>
      <description>As a general election looms, a familiar UK media maelstrom has begun. The key difference here is that the public has been taken by surprise, somewhat - Theresa May’s call for a snap election (we weren’t actually due one until 2020) has left folk with little under two months to decide where their vote will go.
For some, this may be the first election they are able to participate in. For many, the traditional delivery of party politics might not have kept them engaged all that well since the last election.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sentiment Analysis of Kanye West Album Lyrics</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-03-20-kanye_sentiment_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-03-20-kanye_sentiment_analysis/</guid>
      <description>PSA: This blog will cover other stuff besides music, I promise…this post is the fruits of a recent meander into the new ggalt, hrbrthemes and tidytext packages.1
Intro Kanye West is responsible for some of the realest, funniest (“if you fall on the concrete thats your ass fault”…asphalt…anyone?) and inspiring lyrics in music. The strength of these words has had a profound effect on me and my generation. Can the application of sentiment analysis techniques help us understand more about his art?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vinylspotting: A Discogs Fairytale</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-03-01-vinylspotting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-03-01-vinylspotting/</guid>
      <description>At a cursory glance, it’s almost impossible to get much of an understanding of vinyl record collections beyond their size (or perhaps their age, depending on the smell?). If you get up close, you might recognise some artist names or make out some titles on the spines of LPs, but your average collector is gonna have loads of bits that even they don’t recognise on sight. Now, while the unadulterated excitement of finding a white label on the shelve that even you can’t remember is the romance at the very heart of record digging, that thought of forgotten artifacts would send archivists and librarians bonkers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>