<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogdown on ewen</title>
    <link>https://ewen.io/tags/blogdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogdown on ewen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ewen.io/tags/blogdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Advocating for Open Policing with sparklyr and Shiny</title>
      <link>https://ewen.io/blog/2017-07-27-open_policing_sparklyr_shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ewen.io/blog/2017-07-27-open_policing_sparklyr_shiny/</guid>
      <description>I don’t have much reason to dip in to big data processing tools in my current working capacity. Luckily for me, I have a (self-indulgent) blog now - perfect place to scratch these sorts of itches, and then share the resultant mishaps with the whole world.
I’d recently been working on a Shiny app for increasing visibility and engagement with police violence data. It just so happened that I stumbled across Stanford’s Open Policing Project, with some hefty open data ripe for exploring with big data tools, right after the app’s first build was finished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPL Mythbusting with fplR</title>
      <link>https://ewen.io/blog/2017-06-25-fpl_mythbusting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ewen.io/blog/2017-06-25-fpl_mythbusting/</guid>
      <description>I recently authored my first R package (and definitely have the bug, now). It would be remiss of me to continue without a quick PSA for anyone out there thinking about dabbling in the package game - below is a shout-out of the invaluable resources I found along the way that kept me nice and sane.
ease in https://t.co/NdRYGE1whA
more detail https://t.co/ypqotSAF46
best practice https://t.co/qRMZDXBdfQ
travis 💀 https://t.co/dEvM3PWsVb — ewen (@ewen_) June 7, 2017</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sentiment Analysis of Kanye West Records</title>
      <link>https://ewen.io/blog/2017-03-20-kanye_sentiment_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ewen.io/blog/2017-03-20-kanye_sentiment_analysis/</guid>
      <description>PSA: This blog will cover other stuff besides music, I promise…this post is the fruits of a recent meander into the new ggalt, hrbrthemes and tidytext packages.1
Intro Kanye West is responsible for some of the realest, funniest (“if you fall on the concrete thats your ass fault”…asphalt…anyone?) and inspiring lyrics in music. The strength of these words has had a profound effect on me and my generation. Can the application of sentiment analysis techniques help us understand more about his art?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vinylspotting: A Discogs Fairytale</title>
      <link>https://ewen.io/blog/2017-03-01-vinylspotting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ewen.io/blog/2017-03-01-vinylspotting/</guid>
      <description>At a cursory glance, it’s almost impossible to get much of an understanding of vinyl record collections beyond their size (or perhaps their age, depending on the smell?). If you get up close, you might recognise some artist names or make out some titles on the spines of LPs, but your average collector is gonna have loads of bits that even they don’t recognise on sight. Now, while the unadulterated excitement of finding a white label on the shelve that even you can’t remember is the romance at the very heart of record digging, that thought of forgotten artifacts would send archivists and librarians bonkers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>